# Sumaiya Zulfikar

#### FRONT-END ENGINEER

Email: sumaiyaz.here@gmail.com Mob: 0757 829 3080 LinkedIn: in/sumaiyaz Portfolio: sumaiyaz.co.uk

#### **SUMMARY**

Front-end engineer with a passion for crafting intuitive frictionless user experience. Over a decade experience working in product development and engineering teams with sole objective to bringing success to the organisation and achieving remarkable results and delivering value to customers, fast. Skilled in React, Next.js, Node.js, JavaScript, web development principles with a commitment to continuous learning and a collaborative spirit. Eager to contribute my people skills that I developed in past roles coupled with technical skills to solve customer problems and building solutions that deliver value. Looking for front end focused roles.

#### **SKILLS**

- Front-End Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Backend: Node.js, RESTful APIs
- Testing: BrowserStack, Playwright
- Deployment: CI/CD, Netlify, GitHub
- · Agile frameworks: Scrum, Kanban, Design thinking
- Supportive Skills: Problem Solving, Team Collaboration, Stakeholder Communication, KPI and Metrics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full Stack Developer**

MyFund | Aug 2024-present | Remote - Lagos, Financial Services

- Developed Investment webapps modules enhancing user journeys and implementing business logics with React, Redux, Next.js and TypeScript.
- Implemented UI-level validation, interactive elements, and data visualisation for informative user experience.
- Integrated UI components with RESTful APIs using Node.js and Django for seamless data flow.
- Proactively identified and resolved code inconsistencies throughout the application to ensure a unified user experience
  across the application.
- Maintained consistent coding standards, reusable code, and libraries to improve efficiency and maintain brand consistency for new module and feature enhancements.
- Collaborated with cross functional teams to ensure a unified user experience across the web and mobile platforms.
- Conducted code reviews and pair programming for high code quality and a collaborative environment.
- Contributed to bug fixes and debugging to ensure application stability and reliability.

## Front End Developer (Intern)

Dabuka New Horizons | Jun 2024 - Jul 2024 | Remote - Egypt, Tourism

- Implemented SEO best practices such as internal linking, semantics and restructured legacy codebase, achieving a 33% reduction in load time and a 6% increase in organic search ranking.
- Conducted cross-browser testing to identify and resolve functional anomalies.
- Gathered and documented requirements to ensure alignment with business priorities.
- Analysed Google Analytics data to inform business decisions such as highlighting popular packages lead to a 14% increase in traffic
- Proposed technical design solutions for Dabuka's future website considering user experience, maintainability, and cost.

## **Scrum Master**

2017-2023 | London | FinTech and InsurTech

- Coached teams in engineering best practices such as pair programming, code reviews, testing, and estimation, improving
  code quality, efficiency, and standardization, resulting in a 7x increase in productivity.
- Led design sprints to rapidly develop minimum viable products (MVPs), facilitating cross-functional alignment on requirements and ensuring clear understanding among business and technical stakeholders. This streamlined the development process and accelerated time-to-market.
- Established a culture of continuous improvement and optimized processes using DevOps metrics and KPIs, resulting in a significant reduction of support cycle time from 496 days to 3 weeks.

#### **Quality Assurance**

2012-2017 | London

- Reduced Software development life cycle by 75% by implementing Automated regression testing, reducing test execution times.
- Performed quality control by executing Test strategies, test scripts and User acceptance testing.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Job Search Application (React & RESTfulAPIs) | Mar 2024

- Developed a job search application with a user-friendly interface that streamlines the search process. The application efficiently displays relevant information on a single page.
- Integrated API results for a seamless user experience. Results from multiple API sources displayed in a single page to reduce jobseeker friction.
- Peer reviewed and pair programmed with team members for seamless integration, solution design and interconnected components.

Technologies: React, Tailwind CSS, Node.js

GitHub repo: https://github.com/sumzulfikar/Pathway-Application

Live Url: https://pathway-app.netlify.app/

## Modernised Corporate Website (Next.js & TypeScript) – Freelance | Apr 2024

- Migrated a WordPress website to a modern, responsive, and scalable Next.js single-page application, enhancing user engagement.
- Collaborated with content writers for seamless content integration with the new website design.
- Prioritized accessibility for an inclusive user experience.

Technologies: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind, Node.js

Live Url: https://onirban.co.uk

## Digital drawing (HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript) | Jun 2024

- Developed an interactive Etch A Sketch replica using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Canvas API, and Gasp Animation.
- Ensured a mobile-responsive design for a consistent user experience across devices.
- Enhanced user interaction for mobile and desktop users with touch, mouse, and keyboard controls.

GitHub repo: https://github.com/sumzulfikar/etch-a-sketch

Live Url: https://xketchy.netlify.app/

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Bootcamp in Front End Development (Mar 2024) | edX (A+ Grade)

• 16-week programme - HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, React, APIs and Node.js

Jake Knapp's Design Sprint Masterclass

### **EDUCATION**

MSc: Information Systems Management (2008) | Brunel University

BSc: Computer Science (2006) | North South University